Irina Ghose

Sales Excellence Director - Enterprise Business (COO)

Summary

As the Director for Sales Excellence, responsible for defining the Sales Strategy, Planning & Execution for the Enterprise Sales Team. Responsible for Driving World Class Selling, Sales Operations, Inside Sales for Enterprise and Licensing Sales.

Prior to the current role, have been involved with Microsoft for 15+ years in multiple functions spanning Segment Leadership(Education), Business Management, Sales Leadership & Partnerships across various Industry segments.

Previously, worked at Wipro Infotech, HCL Infosystems across Product Management, Business Solutions Consulting, Alliance Management & Sales Management.

Specialties: Strategic Planning, Building Relationships, Conceptualizing & Envisioning new initiatives, Innovation in emerging areas, Sales Management & Execution Excellence, Team Building & Leadership, Driving India centric Innovation.

Experience

Sales Excellence Director - Enterprise Business (COO) at Microsoft

July 2012 - Present (4 years 9 months)

Leading Sales Excellence for Microsoft India Enterprise Business. This function drives Sales Management, Sales Leadership & Operational Excellence. Responsible for Enterprise Business Startegy, Planning, Sales Operations, Inside Sales for Enterprise and Licensing Sales.

Director & Segment Lead- Education at Microsoft

July 2010 - June 2012 (2 years)

As the Director & Segment Lead for Education, led the overall initiatives of Microsoft India in the Education segment. Segment leadership for Microsoft's initiatives across Primary, Secondary and Higher Education across the Private and Government space. This involves working with the Government, Education Institutions, Students, Academicians and the Partner Eco-system to optimize the learning environment by way of technology and innovative solutions. Specific to India, developed specific initiatives towards Skill Building & Digital Literacy.

Director at Microsoft (International Project)

January 2010 - June 2010 (6 months)

Worked in an International Project with the Corporate team in Redmond on the "Application Platform Strategy Planning & Execution Framework with Global SI's for FY11". Worked towards developing the business model, execution planning and implementation with some of the largest Global partners of Microsoft.

Director Sales- South at Microsoft

July 2008 - December 2009 (1 year 6 months)

Responsible for creating the Regional Business Plan, identifying revenue growth drivers, executive relationship management, driving collective vision of a huge cross group towards attaining business goals, partner alignment, establishing sales process and execution framework. Led a team responsible for \$100m of business in Professional Services, BFSI, State Owned Enterprises & Manufacturing across Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad & upcountry locations in the Enterprise Segment.

Corporate Sales Business Head-South at Microsoft

June 2005 - June 2008 (3 years 1 month)

This role had a similar flavour as the one above.

Corpoate Business Manager at Microsoft

July 2003 - June 2005 (2 years)

Account & Relationship Management in Karnataka across various verticals in the Enterprise segment. Foray into non- Microsoft space along with innovative business propositions resulted in significant growth, strong marquee wins, increased market share and multiple "firsts" for Microsoft.

Regional Partner Alliance Manager at Microsoft

December 2001 - June 2003 (1 year 7 months)

Alliance Management involved creating joint Business Plans, GTM planning, joint opportunity addressal, capacity planning & partner readiness. Was also driving a strong alignment with business for the sales rhythm.

Maintained the relationship with some of the largest Platform partners, SI's, ISV's nationally. Created a strong base for Solution Partners portfolio by on-boarding and recruiting new partners across the country.

Business Consultant-eBusiness, Solutions Division at Wipro Infotech Ltd

November 2000 - November 2001 (1 year 1 month)

The job had two flavours towards a vertical and a horizontal focus-

- -Vertical Focus: Banking, Insurance & Equities in India & Equities
- Horizontal Focus: Data warehousing, Content Management, Knowledge Management Was involved in key customer acquisitions in the Finance vertical. Product conceptualization and development of a productized Internet Trading offering. Helped establish replicable frameworks out of Centre of Excellence to gain competitive edge.

Product Manager, Enterprise Products at Wipro Infotech Ltd

October 1999 - October 2000 (1 year 1 month)

Handling Software Products focusing on eBusiness- Sun Software Range, Server Based Computing, Content Management, Streaming Solutions, Ad Management, B2B Solutions, etc. Set up multiple alliances for Wipro.

Led the product development team of an indigenously developed High Availability solution of Wipro.

Business Manager- Corporate Sales ,Laptops and associated Software and Services at HCL Infosystems Ltd

June 1998 - September 1999 (1 year 4 months)

Set up the team in Delhi and created business models for addressing various corporate accounts across segments for the Toshiba range of products & product

Regional Channel Manager, PC Sales for Small and Medium Business at HCL Infosystems Ltd

May 1997 - May 1998 (1 year 1 month)

Established a channel network in Karnataka through partner recruitment, enablement and joint marketing activities. Set up a strong up- country partner base. Was involved in conceptualization & timplementation of promotional events, identifying opportunities of growth in non-traditional segments, and implementing segment based initiatives.

Program Manager in Export Oriented Unit for Large Bid Management for Engineering equipment at Tata Steel

June 1993 - June 1995 (2 years 1 month)

Skills & Expertise

Strategy

Enterprise Software

CRM

Product Management

Go-to-market Strategy

Management

Outsourcing

Leadership

Business Planning

Business Alliances

Sales Operations

Professional Services

Sales Process

Selling

Sales Management

Product Development

Strategic Planning

Sales
Team Building
Project Planning
Building Relationships
Financial Modeling
Cloud Computing
SaaS
Solution Selling
Program Management

Education

XLRI Jamshedpur

MBA, Business Management, 1995 - 1997

Indian Institute of Technology, BHU

Electrical Engineering, 1989 - 1993

Irina Ghose

Sales Excellence Director - Enterprise Business (COO)



Contact Irina on LinkedIn